### ROSIE AFIA CV

Name: Rosie Afia

**Profile:** British National I Full Driving License I Mother tongue English, Basic French & Spanish.

Self-motivated and highly articulate Development Management LSE graduate (MSc) specialising in ICTs and Development. Project management experience illustrates commitment to International Development and demonstrates the capacity to use initiative in the face of time-sensitive objectives. Possesses the ability to multitask, respond to client requirements and a willingness to take responsibility down to the last detail.

### **Experience**

### LSE / Crown Agents, London.

Nov 2013 - Apr 2014

### Student Research Consultant

- Developed LSE research report titled "Public Private Partnerships in Sub-Saharan Africa -In Search of Critical Success Factors" for Crown Agents.
- Included case study analysis of public-private partnerships in three countries in Sub-Saharan Africa.
- Achievements: project expected to lead to partial fulfilment of Masters degree.

# Fitch Learning, London.

Sep 2012 - Sep 2013

#### Client Liaison Assistant

- Bespoke courses team member for the specialist financial training company.
- Responsibilities included; general support to Managing Director, meeting coordination, micro-project management, presentations, assistance with internal / external client contacts. course schedule administration, assistance with course feedback & contracts.
- Achievements: after undertaking a temporary marketing assistant role in 2007 & 2008 was recruited to Client Liaison team. Supported senior management by temporarily acting in the more senior role as Client Liaison Officer while colleague on extended leave. Coordinated various time sensitive projects including extensive exposure to vital legal documentation.

### Riad Chi-Chi, Marrakech.

Jul 2010 - Sep 2010

### General Manager

- · Responsible for administration, accounts, transport, quests & staff as holiday cover for manager.
- Achievements: received excellent published reviews / feedback from guests & employer.

# African Impact (Social Enterprise) & THAF (NGO), Zambia. Jun 2008 - Sep 2009

## Project Designer & Coordinator (African Impact)

- Assisted local management, designed, implemented & managed the HIV & Sport volunteer project. Highly demanding, full-time & live-in job.
- Responsible for up to 30 volunteers, including organising trips to Zimbabwe / Botswana, coordinating staff, transport, visas & project administration.
- Achievements: designed & set-up HIV / Sport project to much acclaim from the community & volunteers. Founded "Livingstone Youth in Sport" charity in order to coordinate tournaments for HIV, malaria & drug awareness for children & women. As a result of the programme's success promoted to sister organisation, The Happy Africa Foundation (THAF).

#### Assistant Manager (THAF).

- Responsible for marketing, admin, accounts, operations & contracts for Zambia's sponsor-a-
- Achievements: implementing efficient systems & procedures, including website design. Initiated process of providing regular feedback & updates for sponsors. Personal fundraising efforts totaled £4000 for the charity. As a result asked to be ambassador to Kenyan programme responsible for contracts & service level agreements for new projects. Created proposals for focal projects & initiated a sponsor-a-teacher programme.

### Project Coordinator.

- Responsible for invoicing / accounts, purchasing & various projects for CEO.
- Achievements: extensive responsibility as member of the accounts team regarding purchasing & payment of invoices. Completed a number of successful marketing projects for the CEO.

# **Internships and Voluntary**

### **Buttons for Hope (NGO), Cape Town.**

Mar 2011 - Apr 2011

### **Project Coordinator**

- Responsible for social media & press exposure for start-up NGO.
- Achievements: established various online platforms for marketing & e-commerce supporting project sustainability.

# Advance Aid (NGO), Nairobi & London.

Jul 2010 & Jul 2011

### Project (research) Coordinator

- As a part-time volunteer responsibilities included assisting CEO with vital meetings with the Kenyan Ministry of Health & researching grants.
- Achievements: being asked to assist CEO in meeting with the head of Kenya's Ministry of Health in order to pitch a 30-second HIV testing kit.

# Alive & Kicking (UK Charity), Nairobi & London.

Jun 2010 - Aug 2010

### **Project Coordinator**

- Coordinated 2-day event (Arsenal in the Community) while based in Nairobi.
- Achievements: successfully raised US\$10,000 for the charity & asked to continue volunteer support on return to London.

### **Education and Qualifications**

# **MSc Development Management, pending**

2013-2014

London School of Economics (LSE).

# **BA Economics & Politics, First Class (Hons)**

2009-2012

University of Leeds.

LSE & Nesta master class	Measuring Social Impact short course	Feb 2014
CodeFirst-Girls	10-week intensive website training course	Jan 2014
Fitch Learning short course	PowerPoint	Jul 2013
Fitch Learning short course	Excel	Jun 2013
Fitch Learning professional course	2-day course on understanding a structured approach to the analysis of Country & Sovereign risk in both emerging & mature markets.	Oct 2012
ONE Advocacy & Campaigns	2-day intensive training on running effective development campaigns.	Nov 2011

## **Hobbies and Other**

- Software proficiency: Confluence, Dreamweaver CS6, Excel, GitHub, Lotus notes, Microsoft Word, Outlook, Powerpoint, SalesForce, SalesLogix, Social Media, SohoLaunch, Sublime Text, SourceTree, Windows & Mac OS systems among others.
- Representative for postgraduate Development Management students (LSE).
- LSE societies: 'DESTIN', 'Business / Social Enterprise' and 'Women Leaders of Tomorrow'.
- Member of the Society of Business Economists (SBE) since 2013.
- Keen sports woman; holder of BASI L2 instructor (snowboarding) qualification with first aid.
- Enjoys adventure; travelled extensively in Africa, Asia, Europe and Latin America.

References available on request.